¬
{Author_1}Jules Brunet, French Advisor to Shogunate Forces
{Author_2}Matsudaira Katamori, Daimyō of Aizu
{Author_3}Yamakawa Hiroshi, Retainer of the Aizu Matsudaira
{Author_4}Nakano Takeko, Onna-bushi of Aizu
{Author_5}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_6}Wilhelm I, German Emperor and King of Prussia on Bismark
{Author_7}Date Yoshikuni, Daimyō of Sendai
{Author_8}Date Yoshikuni, Daimyō of Sendai
{Author_9}Hijikata Toshizō, Vice Commander of the Shinsengumi
{Author_10}William McKinley, President of the United States
{Author_11}William McKinley, President of the United States
{Author_12}Shō Tai, Last King of Ryūkyū
{Author_13}Yoshida Shōin, Samurai of Chōshū
{Author_14}Tự Đức, Emperor of Đại Nam
{Author_15}Victoria, Queen of the United Kingdom and Empress of India
{Author_16}Victoria, Queen of the United Kingdom and Empress of India
{Author_17}Feng Guifen, Qing official and reformer
{Author_18}Feng Guifen, Qing official and reformer
{Author_19}Feng Guifen, Qing official and reformer
{Author_20}Fukuzawa Yukichi, University instructor and witness of the Battle of Ueno
{Author_21}Adolphe Thiers, President of France
{Author_22}Charles Robert Darwin, English Scientist
{Author_23}Alfred Thayer Mahan, American Admiral and Historian
{Author_24}Takasugi Shinsaku, Commander of the Kiheitai
{Author_25}Henry John Temple, 3rd Viscount Palmerston, Twice British Prime Minister
{Author_26}Napoleon III, Emperor of the French
{Author_27}Henry John Temple, 3rd Viscount Palmerston, Twice British Prime Minister
{Author_28}Napoleon III, Emperor of the French; on smoking
{Author_29}Sakamoto Ryoma, Samurai of Tosa                 	
{Author_30}Inukai Tsuyoshi, Military journalist during the Satsuma Rebellion
{Author_31}Napoleon III, Emperor of the French
{Author_32}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher on the coup of Napoleon III
{Author_33}Itagaki Taisuke, Commander of the Jinshōtai
{Author_34}Epitaph of Đỗ Hữu Vị, Captain of the French Foreign Legion 7th Company
{Author_35}Trịnh Văn Cấn, Vietnamese rebel leader
{Author_36}Joseph Athanase Doumer, governor-general of French Indochina and President of France
{Author_37}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher 
{Author_38}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher 
{Author_39}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_40}Zuo Zongtang, Qing general and governor
{Author_41}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_42}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_43}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_44}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_45}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_46}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_47}Friedrich Wilhelm II, Kaiser of Germany
{Author_48}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, Twice British Prime Minister 
{Author_49}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, Twice British Prime Minister 
{Author_50}Cixi, Empress Dowager of the Qing dynasty
{Author_51}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, Twice British Prime Minister 
{Author_52}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, Twice British Prime Minister 
{Author_53}Đỗ Hữu Vị, Captain of the French Foreign Legion 7th Company
{Author_54}William Ewart Gladstone, Four times British Prime Minister 
{Author_55}William Ewart Gladstone, Four times British Prime Minister 
{Author_56}William Ewart Gladstone, Four times British Prime Minister 
{Author_57}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_58}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_59}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_60}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_61}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_62}Henri Duval, French colonial official; on French Indochina
{Author_63}Gunther Plüschow, German aviator
{Author_64}Friedrich Wilhelm II, Kaiser of Germany
{Author_65}Hiram Maxim, British-American inventor
{Author_66}Yoshida Shōin, Samurai of Chōshū
{Author_67}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_68}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_69}Itō Hirobumi, Samurai of Chōshū and 1st Prime Minister of Japan
{Author_70}Yamamoto Yae, Onna-bushi of Aizu
{Author_71}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_72}Charles George Gordon, 'Chinese Gordon'
{Author_73}Charles George Gordon, 'Chinese Gordon'
{Author_74}Charles George Gordon, 'Chinese Gordon'
{Author_75}Charles George Gordon, 'Chinese Gordon'
{Author_76}Henry Morton Stanley, Welsh American Explorer
{Author_77}Henry Morton Stanley, Welsh American Explorer
{Author_78}Henry Morton Stanley, Welsh American Explorer
{Author_79}Shaka kaSenzangakhona,  king of the Zulu Kingdom
{Author_80}Hilaire Belloc, Franco-English writer, "The Modern Traveller"
{Author_81}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet
{Author_82}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet
{Author_83}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet
{Author_84}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The Grave of the Hundred Head"
{Author_85}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The Grave of the Hundred Head"
{Author_86}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The Grave of the Hundred Head"
{Author_87}Joseph Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "Pharaoh and the Sergeant"
{Author_88}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_89}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_90}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_91}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_92}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_93}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_94}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_95}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_96}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_97}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria, King of Bohemia, King of Galicia and Lodomeria, King of Hungary etc.
{Author_98}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria, King of Bohemia, King of Galicia and Lodomeria, King of Hungary etc.
{Author_99}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria, King of Bohemia, King of Galicia and Lodomeria, King of Hungary etc.
{Author_100}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria, King of Bohemia, King of Galicia and Lodomeria, King of Hungary etc.
{Author_101}Le Bien Public, Belgian Newspaper; on the establishment of the Second Mexican Empire
{Author_102}The United States Congress; on the Second Mexican Empire
{Author_103}Maximilian I, Emperor of Mexico
{Author_104}Robert E. Lee, General in Chief of the Armies of the Confederate States
{Author_105}Robert E. Lee, General in Chief of the Armies of the Confederate States
{Author_106}Robert E. Lee, General in Chief of the Armies of the Confederate States
{Author_107}Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States
{Author_108}Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States
{Author_109}William McKinley, President of the United States
{Author_110}Thieu Tri, Emperor of Dai Nam


{Quote_1}A revolution is forcing the Military Mission to return to France. Alone I stay, alone I wish to continue...Soon a reaction will take place, and the daimyō of the north have offered me to be its soul.
{Quote_2}No matter how many people wash the stones with their tears, these names will never vanish from the world.
{Quote_3}Samurai of Satsuma, see with your own bodies: are the swords of Aizu sharp or dull?
{Quote_4}I would not dare to count myself among all the famous warriors - even though I share the same brave heart.
{Quote_5}The poor French...They have not read their Mahan!
{Quote_6}It's hard to be emperor under such a chancellor.
{Quote_7}Though the myriad domains have submitted petitions, Aizu has not been forgiven, and now a nameless order to attack Shōnai has been issued...The gang of Satchō villains has deceived the imperial court, stolen political power, and there is no doubt that they advance their private agenda with cunning and cruelty.
{Quote_8}Therefore it is my intention to join the Northern Alliance, raise great justice and end chaos, and sustain the imperial land. Not only great and small retainers, but the common people as well, should make determination their object and assist me, let there not be any forgetfulness of this.
{Quote_9}I am not going to battle to win. With the Tokugawa government about to collapse, it would be a disgrace if no one is willing to go down with it. That is why I must go. I will fight the best battle of my life to die for the country.
{Quote_10}We need Hawaii just as much and a good deal more than we did California. It is Manifest Destiny.
{Quote_11}The mission of the United States is one of benevolent assimilation.
{Quote_12}The time for wars is ending, the time for peace is not far away. Do not despair. Life itself is a treasure.
{Quote_13}To employ dead old ways to solve problems in a completely changed modern world demonstrates shallow judgement.
{Quote_14}Your county belongs to the Western seas, ours to the Eastern... If you persist in putting the torch to us, disorder will be long.
{Quote_15}It is worth being shot at to see how much one is loved.
{Quote_16}It seems to me a defect in our much famed Constitution, to have to part with an admirable Govt like Ld Salisbury's for no question of any importance or any particular reason, merely on account of the number of votes.
{Quote_17}Why are the Western nations small and yet strong? Why are we large and yet weak? We must search for the means to become their equal, and that depends solely on human effort…
{Quote_18}We have only one thing to learn from the barbarians, and that is strong ships and effective guns.
{Quote_19}A great many of the foreign chiefs have learned our written and spoken language, the best of them can even read our classics and histories. They are able to speak on our dynastic regulations and government administration, on our geography and the state of our people.
{Quote_20}It was our good fortune that the school in Shinsenza was not burned in the combat of the Restoration... In July 1868, there occurred the fierce Battle of Ueno. A few days before and after this event, all theaters and restaurants and places of amusement were closed, and everything was in such a condition that the whole city of 'Eight Hundred and Eight Streets' seemed in utter desolation.
{Quote_21}For those who govern, the first thing required is indifference to newspapers.
{Quote_22}An American monkey, after getting drunk on brandy, would never touch it again, and thus is much wiser than most men.
{Quote_23}Force is never more operative than when it is known to exist but is not brandished.
{Quote_24}Bold and fierce are the [Kiheitai] soldiers -- and what is their intention? Each one offers himself, repaying the nation with his death...It should be our fate to join the ranks of the mourned; how shameful then, to be among the mourners...
{Quote_25}The policy and practice of the Russian Government has always been to push forward its encroachments as fast and as far as the apathy or want of firmness of other Governments would allow it to go, but always to stop and retire when it met with decided resistance and then to wait for the next favorable opportunity.
{Quote_26}Usually, it is man who attacks; as for me, I defend myself, and I often capitulate.
{Quote_27}We have no eternal allies, and we have no perpetual enemies. Our interests are eternal and perpetual, and those interests it is our duty to follow.
{Quote_28}This vice brings in one hundred million francs in taxes every year. I will certainly forbid it at once - as soon as you can name a virtue that brings in as much revenue.
{Quote_29}If you are a man, even if you die in a ditch during battle, you will die pitching forward.
{Quote_30}During the Battle of Tabaruzaka, our forces beseiged a rebel stronghold. We tried to take it, but thirteen rebel soldiers firmly held their ground. Just then, a former Aizu soldier put himself in bodily danger and charged forward, immediately cutting down the thirteen rebels. As he slashed about, he called out loudly, 'Remember the Boshin, remember the Boshin!'... It is said that this Aizu man suffered only slight wounds.
{Quote_31}The Empress is legitimist, my cousin is Republican, Morny is Orleanist, I am a socialist; the only Bonapartist is Persigny, and he is mad.
{Quote_32}History repeats itself, first as tragedy, second as farce.
{Quote_33}The imperial army, fighting under the emperor's gold banner, must not engage in any conduct that would bring shame to the imperial chrysanthemum crest.
{Quote_34}Aviator [Đỗ Hữu Vị]: Died on the field of honour at the Somme; For his homeland Annam, for his fatherland France.
{Quote_35}We must quickly take advantage of this once-in-a-lifetime opportunity. This is a rare opportunity to wash away our humiliation and have our revenge.
{Quote_36}When France arrived in Indochina, the Annamites [Vietnamese] were ripe for servitude.
{Quote_37}It is in this sense that Franklin says, "War is robbery, commerce is generally cheating."
{Quote_38}The redeeming feature of war is that it puts a nation to the test. As exposure to the atmosphere reduces all mummies to instant dissolution, so war passes supreme judgment upon social systems that have outlived their vitality.
{Quote_39}Only a fool learns from his own mistakes. The wise man learns from the mistakes of others.
{Quote_40}We shall first confront [the Russians] with arguments...and then settle it on the battlefield.
{Quote_41}God has a special providence for fools, drunkards, and the United States of America.
{Quote_42}Preventive war is like committing suicide out of fear of death.
{Quote_43}It is the destiny of the weak to be devoured by the strong.
{Quote_44}The secret of politics? Make a good treaty with Russia.
{Quote_45}The great questions of the day will not be settled by means of speeches and majority decisions but by iron and blood.
{Quote_46}People never lie so much as after a hunt, during a war, or before an election.
{Quote_47}It would shame me more to surrender Tsingtao to the Japanese than Berlin to the Russians.
{Quote_48}Like all great travellers, I have seen more than I remember, and remember more than I have seen.
{Quote_49}Everyone likes flattery; and when you come to Royalty you should lay it on with a trowel.
{Quote_50}[The westerners] have started the aggression and the extinction of our nation is imminent. If we just fold our arms and yield to them, I would have no face to see our ancestors after death. If we must perish, why not fight to the death?
{Quote_51}Colonies do not cease to be colonies because they are independent.
{Quote_52}The practice of politics in the East may be defined by one word: dissimulation.
{Quote_53}I must be doubly courageous, for I am both a Frenchman and an Annamite.
{Quote_54}Remember the rights of the savage, as we call him. Remember that the happiness of his humble home, remember that the sanctity of life in the hill villages of Afghanistan, among the winter snows, is as inviolable in the eye of Almighty God, as can be your own.
{Quote_55}All the world over, I will back the masses against the classes.
{Quote_56}Here is my first principle of foreign policy: good government at home.
{Quote_57}“Forward, the Light Brigade!” Was there a man dismayed? Not though the soldier knew, Someone had blundered. Theirs not to make reply, Theirs not to reason why, Theirs but to do and die.
{Quote_58}Cannon to right of them, Cannon to left of them, Cannon in front of them. Volleyed and thundered Stormed at with shot and shell, Boldly they rode and well, Into the jaws of Death, Into the mouth of hell, Rode the six hundred.
{Quote_59}Flashed all their sabres bare, Flashed as they turned in air. Sabring the gunners there, Charging an army, while All the world wondered.
{Quote_60}Plunged in the battery-smoke, Right through the line they broke; Cossack and Russian, Reeled from the sabre stroke, Shattered and sundered.
{Quote_61}When can their glory fade? O the wild charge they made! All the world wondered. Honour the charge they made! Honour the Light Brigade, Noble six hundred!
{Quote_62}Rubber is now king. Our production quotas are nearly met. Coolie workers are harvesting some 1,000 litres [of rubber] a day. They work, on average, 11-12 hours per day and are paid well by local conditions. 
{Quote_63}The next time I was more attentive. And when I saw [a Japanese aviator] close below me, I followed him and shot him down with my Parabellum pistol with 30 rounds.
{Quote_64}When you come upon the enemy, smite him. Pardon will not be given. Prisoners will not be taken. Whoever falls into your hands is forfeit...Make the name 'German' remembered in China for a thousand years so that no Chinaman will ever again dare to even squint at a German.
{Quote_65}The Russians have purchased vast numbers of Maxim guns, and it has been asserted by those who ought to know that more than half of the Japanese killed in the [Russo-Japanese War] were killed with the little Maxim gun.
{Quote_66}Once you asked me when a man should die. With my own death imminent, I have discovered something about death, which I will share with you now. Death is something you should neither fear nor hate. If by living you think that you can perform great deeds, you should live as long as possible. If by dying you think that your deeds should endure, you should be ready to die at any time.
{Quote_67}It is very curious to see how in China and Morocco the vanquished pay for the costs of the expedition that crushed them.
{Quote_68}A People which is content with its homeland and which shreds at even the shadow of a conflict lacks the characteristics of a superior race.
{Quote_69}But those were the days when, in Chōshū, the anti-foreign fever was at its burning point. Throughout the clan, everyone was prepared for war. Not only men, but women also, were armed with spears, with their hair tied up in a white band. A state of actual war reigned.
{Quote_70}The interesting thing about guns is that they make women as strong as men.
{Quote_71}A battle with the Netherlands must be a surprise on our part, we must suddenly present ourselves there with weapons, disrupt the order, and keep the provinces that want to join, let the others go free as they please.
{Quote_72}For a foreign power to take this country [the Sudan] would be most easy. The mass are far from fanatical. They would rejoice in good government, let its religion be what it might …. It is the government that needs civilizing far more than the people.
{Quote_73}The Sudan is a useless possession, ever was so, and ever will be so. . .
{Quote_74}NOW MARK THIS—if the Expeditionary Force, and I ask for no more than 200 men, does not come in 10 days, the town may fall; and I have done the best for the honor of our country. Good Bye
{Quote_75}You can scarcely imagine the beauty and magnificence of the palaces we burnt. It made one’s heart sore just to burn them; in fact, those palaces were so large, and we were so pressed for time, that we could not plunder them carefully.
{Quote_76}Doctor Livingstone, I presume?
{Quote_77}I have arrived at this place from Zanzibar with 115 souls, men, women & children. We are now in a state of imminent starvation. We can purchase nothing from the natives for they laugh at our kinds of cloth....
{Quote_78}We have attacked and destroyed 28 large towns, and 3 or 4 score villages.
{Quote_79}I need no bodyguard at all, for even the bravest men who approach me get weak at the knees and their hearts turn to water, whilst their heads become giddy and incapable of thinking as the sweat of fear paralyzes them.
{Quote_80}Whatever happens, we have got, the Maxim gun, and they have not.
{Quote_81}Nations have passed away and left no traces, And history gives the naked cause of it - One single simple reason in all cases; They fell because their peoples were not fit.
{Quote_82}Take up the white man's burden - Send forth the best ye breed - Go bind your sons to exile To serve your captives' need.
{Quote_83}For it's Tommy this an' Tommy that, and "Chuck 'im out, the brute." But it's "Savior of 'is country," when the guns begin to shoot.
{Quote_84}A Snider squibbed in the jungle, Somebody laughed and fled, And the men of the First Shikaris Picked up their Subaltern dead; With a big blue mark in his forehead And the back blown out of his head. 
{Quote_85}The men of the First Shikaris, Shouted and smote and slew, Turning the grinning jingal On to the howling crew. The Jemadar's flanking-party Butchered the folk who flew. 
{Quote_86}Then a silence came to the river, A hush fell over the shore, And Bohs that were brave departed, And Sniders squibbed no more; For the Burmans said That a white man's head Must be paid for with heads five-score. 
{Quote_87}Said England unto Pharaoh, "I must make a man of you, That will stand upon his feet and play the game; That will Maxim his oppressor as a Christian ought to do," And she sent old Pharaoh Sergeant Whatsisname.
{Quote_88}I am not yet ready to be Tsar. I know nothing of the business of ruling.
{Quote_89}All around me is cowardice and deceit.
{Quote_90}Our blockheads have decided to celebrate the day by parading in the streets with bands of music and red flags.
{Quote_91}I do not rule Russia: Ten thousand clerks do.
{Quote_92}I will preserve the principle of Autocracy as firmly and unflinchingly as my late father.
{Quote_93}You [recruits] have sworn loyalty to me. You have only one enemy and that is my enemy. In the present social confusion, it may come about that I order you to shoot down your own relatives, brothers or parents but even then you must follow my orders without a murmur.
{Quote_94}No quarter will be given! Prisoners will not be taken! Whoever falls into your hands is forfeited. Just as a thousand years ago the Huns under their King Attila made a name for themselves...
{Quote_95}The Tsar is not treacherous but he is weak. Weakness is not treachery, but it fulfils all its functions.
{Quote_96}Shoot down, behead and eliminate the Socialists first, if need be, by a blood-bath, then war abroad.
{Quote_97}Now we can no longer hold back. It will be a terrible war.
{Quote_98}I am the last ruler of the old world.
{Quote_99}My policy is a policy of peace. Everybody should take note of that.
{Quote_100}People say about me: He is old by now, nor does he understand. Then revolutions will break out and it will all be over.
{Quote_101}In a very short time, the monarchy will be so firmly established in Mexico, that one will only be surprised not to have tried it sooner.
{Quote_102}Congress declares that it cannot recognize the founding of a monarchy on the ruins of a Mexican republic with the help of a European power.
{Quote_103}I forgive everyone, and I ask everyone to forgive me. May my blood, which is about to be shed, be for the good of the country. ¡Viva México, viva la independencia!
{Quote_104}It is well that war is so terrible, or we should grow too fond of it.
{Quote_105}I like whiskey. I always did, and that is why I never drink it.
{Quote_106}The consolidation of the states into one vast empire, sure to be aggressive abroad and despotic at home, will be the certain precursor of ruin which has overwhelmed all that preceded it.
{Quote_107}War at the best, is terrible, and this war of ours, in its magnitude and in its duration, is one of the most terrible.
{Quote_108}Without slavery the rebellion could never have existed; without slavery it could not continue.
{Quote_109}Cuba ought to be free and independent, and the government should be turned over to the Cuban people.
{Quote_110}The French are truly a gang of barbarians. Their crimes cannot be pardoned. Any commercial or military ship coming to our shores should be chased away and prevented from landing… Erect more fortifications and artillery of all kinds to protect our coastal defences.


